Ted Hughes papers, 1940-1999
Emory University
- Writings by Ted Hughes, circa 1949-1990, Series 2; Boxes 57-86; OP2-58a; 105-107; OBV1
  - Collected poems, 1957-1995, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 59-80; OP2-28, 105-107
    - "The Unicorn," Notebook of MS (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - "The Unicorn," MS and TS [The Fortieth Anniversary of the Accession of Her Majasty Queen Elizabeth II] [See Subseries 2.3 "Bending to bless Birkhall with hush and prayer" and Subseries 2.4d "The Interpretation of Parables,"] (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - "Notes," MS (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - "Notes," TS (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Rain-Charm for the Duchy, Corrected TS (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - Rain-Charm for the Duchy, Typescript w/ letter from Faber and Faber regarding edits] (Box 78, Folder 15)
    - Rain-Charm for the Duchy, Proofs (2) with corrections (Box OP21)
    - Rain-Charm for the Duchy, Proof 1 (Box OP22)
    - Rain-Charm for the Duchy, Proof 2 (Box OP23)
    - Rain-Charm for the Duchy, Vol. 2 ("The Unicorn"), Galley proof w/ corrections (Box OP24)
    - Three Books (1993)
    - "Abel Cross, Crimsworth Dene," TS [variant title "Where the Mothers"] (Box 78, Folder 16)
    - "Alcomden," TS [variant title: "Rock has not Learned"] (Box 78, Folder 17)
    - "Be a Dry-Fly Puriest," TS (Box 78, Folder 18)
    - "The Bear," MS and TS (Box 78, Folder 19)
    - "The Beacon," TS [variant title "You Claw the Door"] (Box 78, Folder 20)
    - "Bridestones," TS (Box 78, Folder 21)
    - "Caddis," TS (Box 78, Folder 22)
    - "The Canal's Drowning Black," TS (Box 78, Folder 23)
    - "Catadrome," TS (Box 78, Folder 24)
    - "Chinese History of Colden Water," MS and TS (Box 78, Folder 25)
    - "Churn-Milk Joan," TS (Box 78, Folder 26)
    - "Cock-Crows," TS (Box 78, Folder 27)
    - "Crowne Point Pensioners," TS (Box 78, Folder 28)
    - "Dark River," TS (Box 78, Folder 29)
    - "Eighty and Still Fishing for Salmon," TS (Box 78, Folder 30)
    - "Everything's on its Way to the River," MS and TS [See Subseries 2.4: Essays, Reviews and Talks, "Baboons and Neanderthals"] (Box 78, Folder 31)
    - "Familiar," Notebook of MS (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - "Familiar," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.4c: Selected Poems by Keith Douglas] (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - "First, Mills," TS (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - "Flesh of Light," TS (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - "The Gulkana," TS (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - "High Water," MS and TS (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - "Hill-Stone Was Content, TS (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - "Japanese River Tales," TS (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - "Kingfisher," TS (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - "The Long Tunnel Ceiling," TS (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - "Low Water," TS (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - "Madley Singing in the Mountains," MS and TS (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - "The Mayfly is Frail," MS and TS (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - "Milesian Encounter on the Sligachan," TS (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - "The Moorhen," TS (Box 79, Folder 15)
    - "Mount Zion," TS (Box 79, Folder 16)
    - "1984 on 'The Tarka Trail'," MS and TS [variant title "To Educate the Children"] (Box 79, Folder 17)
    - "Performance," TS (Box 79, Folder 18)
    - "A Rival," TS (Box 79, Folder 19)
    - "Salmon Eggs," TS [See also Subseries 1.5: Undated correspondence-Alphabetical, Solatanoff, Ted] (Box 79, Folder 20)
    - "Salmon-taking Times," TS (Box 79, Folder 21)
    - "Shackleton Hill," TS [variant title "Dead farms, dead leaves"] (Box 79, Folder 22)
    - "The Sluttiest Sheep in England," TS (Box 79, Folder 23)
    - "Stanbury Moor," TS [variant title "These Grasses of Light"] (Box 79, Folder 24)
    - "Stealing Trout on a May Morning," TS (Box 79, Folder 25)
    - "Strangers," TS (Box 79, Folder 26)
    - "Stump Pool in April," TS (Box 79, Folder 27)
    - "Tree," TS (Box 79, Folder 28)
    - "Two Trees at Top Withins," TS (Box 79, Folder 29)
    - "Two," TS (Box 79, Folder 30)
    - "Two Photographs of Top Withens," MS and TS [variant title "Top Withins"] [See also Subseries 2.2: Three Books, "Contents list"] (Box 79, Folder 31)
    - "Under the Hill of Centurions," TS (Box 79, Folder 32)
    - "Wadsworth Moor," TS [variant title "Where the Millstone of Sky" and "Midgly Moor"] (Box 79, Folder 33)
    - "Walls at Alcomden," TS [variant title "Hill Walls"] (Box 79, Folder 34)
    - "The West Dart," TS (Box 79, Folder 35)
    - "West Laithe Cobbles," TS [variant title "It is All"] (Box 79, Folder 36)
    - "What's the First Thing You Think Of," TS (Box 79, Folder 37)
    - Three Books, Contents list, MS and TS (Box 79, Folder 38)
    - Three Books, Cave Bird poems, TS (photocopy w/ cut and pasted revisions] (Box 79, Folder 39)
    - Three Books, Cave Bird poems, TS (photocopy) (Box 79, Folder 40)
    - Three Books, Notes, TS (Box 79, Folder 41)
    - Three Books, Typescript (photocopy) (Box 79, Folder 42)
    - Three Books, Corrected galley proof (includes astrological chart) (Box 79, Folder 43)
    - Elmet (1994)
    - "Notes: Elmet," MS and TS (Box 79, Folder 44)
    - "Leaf-Mold," MS and TS [variant title "In Hardcastle Crags, That Echoey Museum" and "The Wreath"] [See also Subseries 2.4c: Selected Poems by Keith Douglas and Subseries 2.4d: Essays, Reviews and Talks, "Baboons and Neanderthals"] (Box 79, Folder 45)
    - "Slump Sundays," TS [See Subseries 2.4: Essays, Reviews and Talks, "Baboons and Neanderthals"] (Box 79, Folder 46)
    - Elmet, Galley proofs w/ corrections (Box 79, Folder 47)
    - Elmet, Final printer's proof (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - New Selected Poems, 1957-1994 (1995)
    - "Anniversary," MS (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - "The Dogs are Eating Your Mother," MS (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - "The God," TS (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - "The Last of the 1st/5th Lancanshire Fusliers," TS (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - "Lines about Elias," MS and TS (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - "Nearly Awake," MS and TS [part of "Astrological Conundrums"] (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - "Old Oats," MS and TS [includes 2 notebooks] (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - "Reckless Head," TS (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - "Remembering Teheran," MS and TS [See also Subseries 1.5: Undated correspondence-Alphabetical, [?], Sir Philip] (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - New Selected Poems, 1957-1994, Poem List (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - New Selected Poems, 1957-1994, Typescript (1 of 3) (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - New Selected Poems, 1957-1994, Typescript (2 of 3) (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - New Selected Poems, 1957-1994, Typescript (3 of 3) (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - New Selected Poems, 1957-1994, Proof with corrections [No. 1] (Box OP25)
    - New Selected Poems, 1957-1994, Proof with corrections [No. 2] (Box OP26)
    - New Selected Poems, 1957-1994, Proof with corrections [No. 3] (Box OP27)
    - New Selected Poems, 1957-1994, Proof with corrections [with letter from Faber & Faber, 7 November 1994] [No. 4] (Box OP28)
  - Uncollected poems, Subseries 2.3; Boxes 81-86; OP29-41
    The subseries consists of manuscript and typescript drafts of uncollected poems of Ted Hughes. Maintaining Hughes' original order, the subseries also includes a grouping of Crow-related poems. If a poem was known by more than one title, the variant title(s) have been provided in brackets. If a poem was made up of, or included, other poems this is also indicated in brackets, thus [includes ...]. Because of Hughes' propensity to reuse paper, cross-references are used to note locations of related materials in other parts of the collection.
    Arranged in alphabetical order by title of the poem, or where there is no title, by the first line.
    - "90 year" [See Subseries 2.2: Wodwo, "Vegetarian"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "About Being Born," MS (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - "Across the Threshold," MS (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - "After all the unlikihood," MS (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - "After all this baloney about him" MS (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - "After the big show" MS (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - "Again and again you lean forward," MS (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - "The air is all arms," MS (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - "All these heroes are the same" MS (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - "All his life and his efforts," MS and notes (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - "All I survey," MS (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - "Allegiance To," MS (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - "Among the leaves where the wasps work," MS [See Subseries 2.3: "When I see you, you'll smile"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "And he steals the blood," MS (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - "And here are the plague burials," MS (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - "And is it a necessity," MS (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - "And the other waved," MS (Box 81, Folder 15)
    - "And when the tropic thunder roars," MS (Box 81, Folder 16)
    - "Annulments inward...," MS (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - "Apotheosis-Buddha masked," TS (Box 81, Folder 18)
    - "The Apple Blossom's Air," MS (Box 81, Folder 19)
    - "Archaeology of the Monet," MS (Box 81, Folder 20)
    - "Arithmetic of Pity," MS and notes (Box 81, Folder 21)
    - "The arrival of baby birds every spring," MS [See Subseries 2.2: Wodwo, "Fern"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "As I walk out to look at the lake," MS (Box 81, Folder 22)
    - "As if there were other something...," MS (Box 81, Folder 23)
    - "As lovely as our own souls," MS (Box 81, Folder 24)
    - "At first it is just luck," MS (Box 81, Folder 25)
    - "At the solstice of each year," MS [See also Subseries 1.5: Ted Hughes' correspondence, 1957-1985] (Box 81, Folder 26)
    - "At University You Had the Wallet," MS [See Subseries 2.3: "Lines to a Newborn baby"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Atavist," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.4c: Selected Poems by Keith Douglas] (Box 81, Folder 27)
    - "The Baby - Trapper," MS (Box 81, Folder 29)
    - "Bad Birth," MS (Box 81, Folder 30)
    - "Ballad of Bauble-Head," TS (Box 81, Folder 31)
    - "The Ballad of Cook's Leap," MS and TS (Box 81, Folder 32)
    - "Balsam," TS (Box 81, Folder 33)
    - "Bare stems of ash," MS (Box 81, Folder 34)
    - "The Battle Field" [See Subseries 2.3: "Memorial Poem for E.W. White"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "B..., the globe one blood-blister," MS (Box 81, Folder 35)
    - "The Begetting of Children," MS (Box 81, Folder 36)
    - "Bending to bless Birkhall with hush and prayer," MS (Box 81, Folder 37)
    - "Beowulf sank from the day," TS (Box 81, Folder 38)
    - "Bet Your Cat" [See Subseries 2.7: Camillo Pennati Poems, "Blond Autumn"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Between her footsoles and her crown," MS (Box 81, Folder 39)
    - "Between Luxor and Karnak," MS and TS (Box 81, Folder 40)
    - "Between Showers," MS [See also Subseries 2.4c: Vasko Popa, Selected Poems, MS drafts] (Box 81, Folder 41)
    - "Between Two or Three Birches," MS (Box 81, Folder 42)
    - "The big tit," MS (Box 81, Folder 43)
    - "Bill is nearly eighty," MS (Box 81, Folder 44)
    - "Biography," TS (Box 81, Folder 45)
    - "Birdsong" MS and TS [variant titles: "Love Song" and "First, love is a little bird"] (Box 81, Folder 46)
    - "Birth is the gate of life," MS (Box 81, Folder 47)
    - "The Black Oak" [See Subseries 2.2: Wodwo, "Ballad from a Fairy Tale"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Blizzard of dry tails" and "The Executioner Sickens," MS (Box 81, Folder 48)
    - "Born the same day as the princess," MS (Box 81, Folder 49)
    - "Bottom's Lullaby," MS (Box 81, Folder 50)
    - "The Bride," MS (Box 81, Folder 51)
    - "The bridegroom's flayed, purpled, silvery head," TS (Box 81, Folder 52)
    - "A Bronze Caste of Selous" [variant title: "A Kill"], MS and TS (Box 81, Folder 53)
    - "The Brother's Dream," MS and TS [variant titles: "The Bear," "The Brother's Dream-Poem," and "Event in a Cave - Drama"; see also Subseries 2.3: "Crow Goes to the Movies" and "Sorrow" and Subseries 2.5: "A Bedtime Story," drafts] (Box 81, Folder 54)
    - "Bullocks of Flint Hooves," MS (Box 81, Folder 55)
    - "But but but, MS (Box 81, Folder 56)
    - "But it is not interested," MS (Box 81, Folder 57)
    - "Camouflage is death's 5th column," MS (Box 81, Folder 58)
    - "The Captain's Speech," TS (Box 81, Folder 59)
    - "Captured by dumb odors of herbage," MS (Box 81, Folder 60)
    - "The Car Is Falling to Pieces," MS (Box 81, Folder 61)
    - "The Carpet Is Happy," MS (Box 81, Folder 62)
    - "Cars," TS (Box 81, Folder 63)
    - "A Castle," MS and TS [variant titles: "Fort" and "Castle"] [See also Subseries 2.4c: Selected Poems by Keith Douglas] (Box 81, Folder 64)
    - "Cattle immobilised under sleet," TS (Box 81, Folder 65)
    - "Causley at 70," MS and TS (Box 81, Folder 66)
    - "Ceasar with his sword was bleeding," MS (Box 81, Folder 67)
    - "Chiliastic," MS (Box 81, Folder 68)
    - "The city was a cement mixer," MS [See Subseries 2.3: "Tar Girl"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Clare on Swallows," TS and "Michael on Swallows," TS (Box 81, Folder 69)
    - "The Clever Fox," MS and TS (Box 81, Folder 70)
    - "The clock says 'When will it be morning'", MS (Box 81, Folder 71)
    - "Cobweb of Evening Air," MS (Box 81, Folder 72)
    - "Cock," MS [See Subseries 2.6, What is the Truth, "Badger"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Cold April" MS (Box 81, Folder 73)
    - "A cold church," MS [See Subseries 2.3: "Three Things Time Will Not Spare"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Coldness of the Sea" MS [See Subseries 2.3 "Yorick"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "A common pebble of the ford" [See Subseries 2.2: Wodwo, "Thistles" and Subseries 2.3 "All these heros are the same"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Concurrence," TS (Box 81, Folder 74)
    - "Conger Eel," TS (Box 81, Folder 75)
    - "Conscripts," TS [See Subseries 2.4: Essays, Reviews and Talks, "Baboons and Neanderthals"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Could God be vegetable..." MS [See Subseries 2.2: Wodwo, "Public Bar T.V."] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Couplets to a new-born baby," TS [See Subseries 2.2: Recklings, "Unknown Soldier"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Cuckoo," TS [different than "Cuckoo" as published in The Cat and the Cuckoo and New Selected Poems (1995)] (Box 81, Folder 76)
    - "Cup of Tea Song," MS (Box 81, Folder 77)
    - "Cy has swallowed the sun," MS (Box 81, Folder 78)
    - "The Dancer Alights," MS (Box 81, Folder 79)
    - "Dark House" [See Subseries 2.3: "Keeping Its Twenty Year Siege"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Day by day I added" [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] [Unpublished Gaudette poem?] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The day was cold, the month March" MS (Box 81, Folder 80)
    - "Dazed August afternoons, the sun in possession" MS (Box 81, Folder 81)
    - "The Dead Are Cynical," MS (Box 81, Folder 82)
    - "A death this second head over heels," MS (Box 81, Folder 83)
    - "The deaf children," MS (Box 81, Folder 84)
    - "Defending yourself, your children," MS (Box 81, Folder 85)
    - "The Deferred Upstart," TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Tiger's Bones, MS] (Box 81, Folder 86)
    - "Des Montespan, Louis' ousted mistress," MS [See also Subseries 2.2: Wodwo, "Thistles"] (Box 81, Folder 87)
    - "Determination's a termite" MS [See Subseries 2.3 "And is it a necessity"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Devon Riviera" [See Subseries 2.4c: Selected Poems by Keith Douglas] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Dialogue Between Priest and Emile" [See Subseries 2.3: "Tar Girl"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Dice," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Woodwo, "The Green Wolf"] (Box 81, Folder 88)
    - "Difficulties of Aphrodite," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Difficulties of a Bridegroom," TS (Box 81, Folder 89)
    - "Digging," MS [See also Subseries 2.3: "I hear how crow sings"] (Box 81, Folder 90)
    - "Disarmament," MS and TS [variant titles: "Natural History," "Tyrants Skulls," and "Skulls"] (Box 81, Folder 91)
    - "Do Bees Ever Strike," MS and various verses (Box 81, Folder 92)
    - "The dog not put to sleep," MS [See Subseries 2.3: "You kept well what your parents bequeathed"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Douser," MS (Box 81, Folder 93)
    - "The Dramatic," MS (Box 81, Folder 94)
    - "Dropped All This Way From the Cradle," MS (Box 81, Folder 95)
    - "The Drowned Woman," TS [See Subseries 2.3 "Gulls"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Dry wreck," MS [See Subseries 2.3: "There is nothing to be done about people"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Each limb of the tiger," MS (Box 81, Folder 96)
    - "Encounter With a Boer," TS (Box 81, Folder 98)
    - "Entering Southampton, the gulls," MS [See Subseries 2.3: "Des Montespan, Louis' ousted mistress"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Episodes From the Life of a Violin," TS (Box 81, Folder 99)
    - "Epithalamium," TS [See Subseries 2.3: "Positivists"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Era of Giant Lizards," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Recklings, "Fishing at Dawn"] (Box 81, Folder 100)
    - "Eskimo Snow Story," TS (Box 81, Folder 101)
    - "Even so he said it was enough," MS (Box 81, Folder 102)
    - "Everything that is not his rock," MS (Box 81, Folder 103)
    - "Everything was useful," MS (Box 81, Folder 104)
    - "The Executioner Has Inhaled Germs," MS (Box 81, Folder 105)
    - "Exocism," MS [See Subseries 2.3: "A Jaw, Nose, undershot well out into the air"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Expedition to the Pole" [See Subseries 2.3: "Not Comforting Company but Fatal Abutment"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Extinct Religion," MS (Box 81, Folder 107)
    - "Eyes," MS (Box 81, Folder 108)
    - "The Eyes are...," MS (Box 81, Folder 109)
    - "The Eyes of the Jury," MS (Box OP29)
    - "A Fable," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Wodwo, "Thistles"] (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - "Facts About the Oak," MS (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - "Fighting for Jerusalem," MS (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - "First April," TS [See Subseries 2.6 The Iron Man: MS] (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - "First Come the Gods," MS (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - "First Light, Earth Twins," MS (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - "First Things First," MS and TS (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - "First Things First," MS (Box OP30)
    - "The flash startles," (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - "The Flow Was Low," MS (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - "The Flower Poems," MS and TS [Includes "Buttercup", "Primroses", "Apple Blossom", "Violet", and "Pear"] (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - "Folk-Lore," TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Price of a Bride (?), MS] (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - "For Conrad, 9th March 1984," MS (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - "For Jennifer, Nothing Has Changed," MS (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - "A Forced Wedding Feast," MS [See Subseries 2.3 "The Bride"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Forty Years as a Leading Actress," MS (Box 82, Folder 14)
    - "Frieda Sleeps," MS and TS (Box 82, Folder 15)
    - "From All Lovers of Salmon For Gruimunder Einksson," (on his retirement from the Presidency of Nasco) MS and TS (Box 82, Folder 16)
    - "From smiles from concessions from soft sheep," MS (Box 82, Folder 17)
    - "From whose head," MS (Box 82, Folder 18)
    - "Frosty morning" [See Subseries 2.2: Wodwo, "Ludwig's Death-Mask," MS [OP2] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Full House," Part I: "Queen of Hearts," MS (Box 82, Folder 18a)
    - "Full House," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "The Black Rhino," MS and Subseries 2.4c: Selected Poems by Keith Douglas] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The German at his yacht," (Box 82, Folder 19)
    - "Giant Dream of Elephants," MS and TS (Box 82, Folder 20)
    - "The Gibbons," TS (Box 82, Folder 21)
    - "Gibraltar," MS and TS and other TS poem fragments ["Neighbour" ("The sea glooms and presses") and "September"] [See also Subseries 2.2: Recklings, "A Colonial"] (Box 82, Folder 22)
    - "The girls in the square are in their first summer," MS (Box 82, Folder 23)
    - "Gladiator," MS (Box 82, Folder 24)
    - "The Gnarled Icicle," MS (Box 82, Folder 25)
    - "Go???ly she arrives-," MS (Box 82, Folder 26)
    - "A God who has nothing to learn and cannot learn," MS (Box 82, Folder 27)
    - "God, you say, must have given this face," MS [See Subseries 2.3: "A Little Lunar Cantata"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The godly thing in conscience keep" MS fragments [See Subseries 2.4c: Selected Poems by Keith Douglas] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "God's face smiled on Eden," MS (Box 82, Folder 28)
    - "Gods Gods great and small," TS and carbon copy (about Oedipus but does not appear to be from Seneca's Oedipus) (Box 82, Folder 29)
    - "Goodbye Jesus," MS (Box 82, Folder 30)
    - "Goodbye letters...the blown glow," MS (Box OP31)
    - "Goodbye, she says goodbye," MS (Box 82, Folder 31)
    - "The Granite Moon Is Older than the Mountains," MS (Box 82, Folder 32)
    - "The Great Irish Pike" MS and TS (Box 82, Folder 33)
    - "The grey wood pigeon's body bears," MS (Box 82, Folder 34)
    - "Gulls," MS and TS (Box 82, Folder 35)
    - "Hamlet's Soliloquy I," MS (Box 82, Folder 36)
    - "Hand," MS (Box 82, Folder 37)
    - "Having Pronounced That," MS (Box 82, Folder 38)
    - "He didn't know it was himself reborn [See Subseries 2.3: General notes] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "He does not move," MS (Box 82, Folder 39)
    - "He gazed round, the tall young German," MS (Box 82, Folder 40)
    - "He is a Butcher," MS (Box 82, Folder 41)
    - "He is blind: He kneels," MS (Box 82, Folder 42)
    - "He Loiters at the Door," MS (Box 82, Folder 43)
    - "He sees," MS (Box 82, Folder 44)
    - "He stopped, the church spire had bobbed" MS (Box 82, Folder 45)
    - "He was nowhere to be found," MS (Box 82, Folder 46)
    - "Heavier in flesh," MS [See Subseries 2.2: Wodwo, "Public Bar T.V."] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Heirlooms," MS (Box 82, Folder 47)
    - "He regards his hands and feet" [See Subseries 2.3: "Something is at the ear wobbly"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Her Dream," TS [See Subseries 2.2: Remains of Elmet, "Lumb Chymneys"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Her eyes were afraid," MS (Box 82, Folder 48)
    - "Her nerves..." MS (Box 82, Folder 49)
    - "Her Speech Is Spells Tumbled," MS [TH notes: lines about S.[uzette] M.] (Box 82, Folder 50)
    - "Her Wedding Was Blue Dull Rain" MS and "To Be Eaten By a Crocodile," MS (Box 82, Folder 51)
    - "Here Is the Eye Whose Wideness," MS (Box 82, Folder 52)
    - "Here She Comes and the Secret She Disappeared," MS (Box 82, Folder 53)
    - "Here stood the Irish elk," TS [See Subseries 2.3: "Her eyes were afraid"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Heroes" MS (Box 82, Folder 54)
    - "His hands" MS (Box 82, Folder 55)
    - "His hopes unlike everybody else's," MS (Box 82, Folder 56)
    - "History's Bad Name," MS (Box 82, Folder 57)
    - "Horrible accidents-just one glimpse," TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] [Unpublished Gaudette poem?] (Box 82, Folder 58)
    - "The Hot Panther Black," MS (Box 82, Folder 59)
    - "How Can I Welcome You," MS (Box 82, Folder 60)
    - "How Did My Aunt Acquire That Smile of Hers" MS [See Subseries 2.3 "A Man Brought to His Knees in the Desert"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "How Many Loves Were There," MS (Box 82, Folder 61)
    - "How much too old is the oak?" MS (Box 82, Folder 62)
    - "How my blood went-it came first," MS (Box 82, Folder 63)
    - "How slow the wind," MS (Box 82, Folder 64)
    - "How to Eat" [See Subseries 2.3: "In Those First Days When a Newborn Baby Still Follows its Mother"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "A hundred times re-entering and leaving," TS [See also Subseries 2.3: "And he steals the blood" and Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] [Unpublished Gaudette poem?] (Box 82, Folder 65)
    - "Hungry For Sunlit Wall," MS (Box 82, Folder 66)
    - "A Hurtling Head," TS (Box 82, Folder 67)
    - "I am an ungrateful woman,"MS [See Subseries 2.3: "Sunday"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "I Bid This Fairy Go," MS (Box 82, Folder 68)
    - "I Came In Peace and Required Nothing," MS (Box 82, Folder 69)
    - "I did all that I thought I wanted to do," TS [See Subseries 2.6: What is the Truth?, "Hare"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "I don't want to come with you," MS (Box 82, Folder 70)
    - "I feel your eye," TS (Box 82, Folder 71)
    - "I Follow My Brain...," MS (Box 82, Folder 72)
    - "I have a Grandaddy far in the North," MS (Box 82, Folder 73)
    - "I have become deaf," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)